Guide to the Minnie Bruce Pratt Papers, 1870s-2005, bulk 1975-2005 RL.01046
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Writing Series, 1960-2005 and undated, 50 boxes
  - Walking Back Up Depot Street, 1979-1999 and undated, 6 boxes
    - A Shrine/A Garden in the City, 1997 June (Box 25)
    - The Value of Use, 1997 September-December (Box 25)
    - Walking Back Up Depot Street, draft, 1997 December (Box 25)
    - Red String, 1997 December 5 (Box 25)
    - The Remnant Shop, 1997 December 22 (folder 1 of 2) (Box 25)
    - The Remnant Shop, 1997 December 22 (folder 2 of 2) (Box 26)
    - The Gate, 1998 July (Box 26)
    - Walking Back Up Depot Street, Bino's critiques, 1998 July (Box 26)
    - Walking Back Up Depot Street revisions, 1998 July 22-29 (Box 26)
    - Walking Back Up Depot Street revisions and editing, 1998 July 26-29 (Box 26)
    - Walking Back Up Depot Street draft, 1998 August 12 (Box 26)
    - Walking Back Up Depot Street production, 1998 September-1999 April (Box 26)
    - Walking Back Up Depot Street revisions, 1998 October 26 (Box 26)
    - Walking Back Up Depot Street page proofs, 1998 November-December (Box 26)
    - Walking Back Up Depot Street first proofs, 1998 December (Box 26)
    - Announcements for reading and book party, New York, NY, 1999 April 10 (Box 26)
    - Walking Back Up Depot Street, hardcover, 1999 (Box 26)
    - Walking Back Up Depot Street, paperback, 1999 (Box 27)
    - City of Emptiness, undated (Box 27)
    - Church, undated (Box 27)
    - Death Row, undated (Box 27)
    - Painting Her Fingernails Red, undated (Box 27)
    - Pokeweed by the Fence, undated (Box 27)
    - Snowed In, undated (Box 27)
    - The Suicide and the Garden, undated (Box 27)
    - Summer/Cup of Her Body, undated (Box 27)
    - Taking Back the Night, undated (Box 27)
    - Book cover (Oversize-box 1)
  - The Dirt She Ate, 2001-2003 and undated, 2 boxes
    The Dirt She Ate compiles poetry from Pratt's four previous books of poems and adds thirteen new poems, providing an overview of her career as a poet through 2003. The subseries also contains Pratt's 2003 chapbook, The Money Machine. Materials in the subseries include drafts, notes, and correspondence. Files are arranged chronologically.
    - A Woman on Foot, commented draft, 2001 July 23 (Box 27)
      Alternate title for The Dirt She Ate.
    - Poem selections for The Dirt She Ate with comments, 2001 July 26 (Box 27)
    - Correspondence with selected editors, 2001 July-August (Box 27)
    - I Am the Only Danger, commented poem selections and notes, 2001 July-August (Box 27)
    - The Dirt She Ate, edited draft, 2001 October 11 (Box 27)
    - The Dirt She Ate, edited draft under other possible titles and notes, 2001 October 12 (Box 27)
    - Correspondence regarding book cover and photographs of Pratt, 2002 May-August (Box 28)
    - The Dirt She Ate: Selected and New Poems, edited draft, 2002 July 29 (Box 28)
    - Correspondence, 2002-2003 (Box 28)
    - The Dirt She Ate, edited proof, 2003 (Box 28)
    - The Dirt She Ate, paperback, 2003 (Box 28)
    - The Money Machine: Selected Poems, Belladonna #46, 2003 Spring (Box 28)
      Only two silver Belladonna chapbooks exist, one located here and the other retained by Pratt.
    - Poem selections, undated (3 folders) (Box 28)
    - Book cover (Oversize-box 1)
  - Feminary, 1973-1988 and undated, 3 boxes
    Feminary was an editorial collective based in Durham, North Carolina that self-published a local feminist newsletter. Pratt was actively involved in Feminary from 1978 to 1983, by which point the newsletter had developed into a quarterly journal. In addition to feminism, the collective focused on anti-racism, anti-imperialism, and lesbianism. Pratt also had early involvement in Feminary from 1972-1973 during its original newsletter form. The subseries contains correspondence, submissions, a run of Feminary newsletters and journals, and The Newsletter. Correspondence and submissions are arranged chronologically, followed by runs of the two titles, each arranged chronologically. The Newsletter was not published by the Feminary collective, but was a similarly self-published newsletter created by the group Triangle Area Lesbian Feminists (of Chapel Hill, Durham, and Raleigh, NC). Pratt maintained her collection of The Newsletter with her Feminary materials, and this connection was retained in the subseries.
    - Submissions, correspondence, and minutes, 1978-1980 (3 folders) (Box 29)
    - Correspondence, 1979-1984 (2 folders) (Box 29)
    - Taping for the blind, 1979 (Box 29)
    - Black women poets/writers, 1980-1981 (Box 29)
    - Submissions, 1982-1984 (Box 29)
    - Notes on newsletter, 1973-1978 (Box 30)
    - Feminary, volume 4-15, 1973 February 12-1985 (6 folders) (Box 30)
      Also titled Feminist Newsletter (1973-1974) and A Feminary (1975).
    - The Newsletter, volume 1-7, 1981 October 1-1988 August (7 folders) (Box 31)
    - The Newsletter, other volumes, 1988 (Box 31)
    - Poster (Oversize-box 1)
  - Workers World, 1994-2005, 3 boxes
    By 2008, Pratt wrote a multitude of articles for Workers World newspaper as a contributing editor. The newspaper is published by Workers World Party, a communist party founded in 1959 that is active in the struggle for the rights of oppressed people. The subseries is arranged chronologically and contains article drafts, printed articles, and research clippings.
    - Articles, 1994-1998 (Box 32)
    - Articles, 2001-2002 (3 folders) (Box 32)
    - Articles, 2003 (2 folders) (Box 32)
    - Articles, 2004 (folder 1 of 5) (Box 32)
    - Articles, 2004 (folders 2-5 of 5) (Box 33)
    - Articles, 2005 (folders 1-2 of 4) (Box 33)
    - Articles, 2005 (folders 3-4 of 4) (Box 34)
  - Other Writings, 1975-2005 and undated, 3 boxes
    The Other Writings subseries comprises miscellaneous writings not associated with books covered in other subseries, journals, gigs, and editorial work. The subseries includes drafts, articles, speeches, poems, essays, as well as material related to her work on the board of Feminist Studies. Materials are organized chronologically.
    - Miscellaneous prose drafts, 1975-1977 (Box 34)
    - Published poems, 1977-1981 (Box 34)
    - Encyclopedia of American Women Writers, 1978-1979 (Box 34)
    - Read to Write review, 1979 September-October (Box 34)
    - Chi Omega Article, 1979 (Box 34)
    - Astarte's Huge Laboratory: Some Thoughts on Mothers, Daughters, and Amazons in the South, Southeastern Women's Studies Association Conference, 1979-1980 (Box 34)
    - At the Big Star, 1980 (Box 34)
    - Yours in Struggle, 1980 October-1983 December (Box 34)
    - Women's Pentagon Action, 1981-1983 (Box 34)
    - Hats/Veils, 1982 (Box 34)
    - Women writers: Rita Mae Brown, Margaret Mitchell, Charlotte Bronte, Maureen Brady, Nadine Gordimer, Michelle Cliff, 1982-1988 (Box 34)
    - Poems for friends, 1983-1987 (Box 34)
    - Poems for Joan, 1985 December-1988 February (Box 34)
    - Bridges advisory board, 1989-1998 (Box 34)
    - On Accepting the Lamont Award for Poetry, As a Lesbian at the Guggenheim, 1989 May 16 (2 folders) (Box 35A)
    - The Buried Yes, The Feminist Memoir Project, 1994-1998 (Box 35A)
    - Dorothy Allison, The Progressive, 1995 July (Box 35A)
    - Yours in Struggle reprint, 2000-2004 (2 folders) (Box 35A)
    - Photographs of New York by Leslie Feinberg, 2004 Autumn (Box 35A)
    - Feminist Studies Board correspondence, 2005 (2 folders) (Box 35B)
    - Feminist Studies Board submissions, 2005 (folder 1 of 2) (Box 35B)
    - Feminist Studies Board submissions, 2005 (folder 2 of 2) (Box 36)
    - The Forbidden poems, undated (Box 36)
    - Introduction to Joan's book, drafts, and galley proofs, undated (Box 36)
    - Love for the World and We Are In It: Adrienne Rich's Work of Repair, undated (Box 36)
    - Miscellaneous notes, undated (2 folders) (Box 36)
    - Speech, feminist utopias, undated (Box 36)
  - Grant Applications, 1980-2003, 2 boxes
    Pratt frequently applied for grants to support herself financially as a writer. The Grant Applications subseries includes grant and fellowship applications arranged chronologically.
    - Miscellaneous, 1980-2002 (Box 36)
    - Fund for Southern Communities application for Night Heron Press, 1982-1983 (Box 36)
    - Money for Women/Barbara Deming Memorial Fund, 1984, 1999 (Box 36)
    - Guggenheim, 1991-2003 (Box 36)
    - D.C. Commission on the Arts and Humanities, 1992-1993 (Box 36)
    - Puffin Foundation, 1993-2001 (Box 36)
    - New Jersey State Council on the Arts, 1999-2003 (Box 36)
    - National Endowment for the Arts, 2000-2002 (Box 37)
    - Writer's Voice residency, 2001 (Box 37)
  - Interviews, 1983-2002, 1 boxes
    The Interviews subseries comprises drafts and print interviews written by other individuals about Pratt. The subseries is arranged chronologically.
    - Miscellaneous print interviews, 1983-2002 (4 folders) (Box 37)
    - Laura Benkov, 1993-1994 (Box 37)
    - In Conversation, On Our Backs, 1995 March (Box 37)
    - Elly Bulkin, 1999 (Box 37)
  - Gigs, 1976-2005, 13 boxes
    The Gigs subseries contains materials related to Pratt's speaking and conference appearances. The chronologically arranged materials primarily consist of negotiations and correspondence pertaining to Pratt's appearances, as well as program materials and speech drafts. Pratt's frequent speaking appearances allowed her to support herself financially as a writer, and also to publicize her work through readings.
    - PR, 1976-1983 (Box 37)
    - Womanwrites, 1979 (Box 38)
    - National Women's Studies Association (NWSA), 1980 (Box 38)
    - Fayetteville, North Carolina, 1980-1981 (Box 38)
    - Southern Lesbian Poets Workshop, 1981 January 4 (Box 38)
    - Pagoda conference, 1981 (Box 38)
    - Women in Print, 1981 (Box 38)
    - Poetry readings, 1982 (Box 38)
    - Womanwrites, 1982 (Box 38)
    - Midwest, 1982 Spring (Box 38)
    - Midwest, 1982-1985 (Box 38)
    - Common Differences, 1983 (Box 38)
    - Conferences/workshops, 1983 (Box 38)
    - Southern Lesbian Conference, 1983-1984 (Box 38)
    - South, 1983 Fall (2 folders) (Box 38)
    - Northeast, 1983 (Box 39)
    - Readings, 1983-1992 (Box 39)
    - East coast, 1984 (Box 39)
    - West Virginia/Kentucky/Ohio, 1984 (Box 39)
    - Conferences, 1984 (Box 39)
    - PR, 1984-1993 (3 folders) (Box 39)
    - Conferences, 1985 (Box 39)
    - South East, 1986 Spring (Box 39)
    - Conferences/workshops, 1986 (Box 40)
    - Community Writers' Project, 1986-1992 (Box 40)
    - Conferences/workshops, 1987 (Box 40)
    - Ninth Annual Southeastern Lesbian Writers' Conference, 1987 May 28-31 (Box 40)
    - Ithaca, Oberlin, Penn, Oswego, 1988 (Box 40)
    - New York, 1988 (Box 40)
    - Conferences/workshops, 1988-1989 (Box 40)
    - Northeast and southeast, 1989 (Box 40)
    - Boston, Binghamton, 1990 (Box 40)
    - OutWrite, San Francisco and Los Angeles, 1990 (Box 40)
    - Northwest (including Gay Games), 1990 (2 folders) (Box 40)
    - East coast, 1990-1991 Spring (Box 40)
    - Midwest, 1990-1991 (Box 41)
    - Northeast, 1991 Fall (Box 41)
    - Readings, 1991-1996 (Box 41)
    - 1992 (3 folders) (Box 41)
    - Astraea, 1993 (Box 41)
    - Poets-Writers, Inc. competition (judge), 1993 (Box 41)
    - 1993-1994 (folder 1 of 2) (Box 41)
    - 1993-1994 (folder 2 of 2) (Box 42)
    - South, 1993-1995 (Box 42)
    - OutWrite, 1993, 1995 (Box 42)
    - PR, 1993-1997 (2 folders) (Box 42)
    - Camp Trans, 1994-1995 (Box 42)
    - New York, New Jersey, 1994-1996 (Box 42)
    - California, 1994-1995 (2 folders) (Box 42)
    - Poetry Society of America (judge), 1994-1997 (Box 42)
    - Virginia, North Carolina, 1995 (Box 42)
    - Midwest, 1995 (Box 43)
    - Baltimore/D.C./Philadelphia, 1995 (Box 43)
    - Midwest, 1995-1996 (Box 43)
    - OutWrite, 1996 (Box 43)
    - Goethe Institut, Chicago, 1996 (Box 43)
    - Spring and Fall, 1996 (3 folders) (Box 43)
    - Guild Complex, Chicago, 1997 (Box 43)
    - Germany, 1997 (Box 43)
    - University of Pennsylvania, 1997 (Box 44)
    - Queer Student Leadership Summit, Eastern Michigan University, 1997 (Box 44)
    - Midwest, 1997 (Box 44)
    - 1997 (Box 44)
    - Readings, 1997-2005 (Box 44)
    - 1998 (Box 44)
    - OutWrite, 1999 (Box 44)
    - West Coast, 1999 (Box 44)
    - Northwest, 1999 (Box 44)
    - 1999 (Box 44)
    - Web page, 1999 (Box 45)
    - New York/Northeast, 1999-2000 (2 folders) (Box 45)
    - Italy, 1999-2001 (Box 45)
    - West Coast, 2000 (2 folders) (Box 45)
    - Atlanta, 2000 (Box 45)
    - Texas, 2000 (Box 45)
    - Taiwan, 2000-2004 (folder 1 of 3) (Box 45)
    - Taiwan, 2000-2004 (folders 2-3 of 3) (Box 46)
    - 2001 (2 folders) (Box 46)
    - Spring 2002-Fall 2003 (4 folders) (Box 46)
    - Provincetown, 2003 (Box 46)
    - Wisconsin, 2003 (2 folders) (Box 47)
    - Women's Fight Back Network, 2003 March 22 (Box 47)
    - St. Louis, 2003 (Box 47)
    - Rose Gladney lecture, 2004 (Box 47)
    - Cornell, 2004 (Box 47)
    - Oshkosh, 2004 (Box 47)
    - Italy, 2004 (2 folders) (Box 47)
    - 2004 (folder 1 of 3) (Box 47)
    - 2004 (folders 2-3 of 3) (Box 48)
    - Femme Conference, Seattle, 2005 (2 folders) (Box 48)
    - Syracuse, 2005 (Box 48)
    - The Scholar and the Feminist, New York, 2005 (Box 48)
    - Minnesota, 2005 (Box 48)
    - 2005 (folder 1 of 4) (Box 48)
    - 2005 (folders 2-4 of 4) (Box 49)
  - Manuscripts by Others, 1974-2005 and undated, 2 boxes
    The subseries contains writings by individuals other then Pratt that were sent to her for her perusal or commentary, or because the work discusses Pratt's work, including a late draft of Dorothy Allison's Bastard Out of Carolina with Pratt's remarks. The subseries comprises a variety of writings, including drafts of books, poems, short stories, essays, and literature reveiws. Materials are organized alphabetically by the last name of the sender or author.
    - Allison, Dorothy, Bastard Out of Carolina, revised draft, 1991 August (4 folders) (Box 49)
    - Anderson, Kelly, Voices of Feminism Oral History Project, interview transcript, 2005 March 16-17 (2 folders) (Box 49)
    - Arcana, Judith, What If Your Mother, draft copy, undated (Box 49)
    - ASTRAEA National Lesbian Action Foundation, Lesbian Writers Fund Awards, manuscript submissions, 1992 (Box 50)
    - Caldwell, Jaye Rogers, Social Darwinism and the Economics of Colonialism, literature review, 2004 Winter (Box 50)
    - Cruikshank, M. L. (sender), short stories by various writers, 1978-1979 (Box 50)
    - Deming, Barbara, Travail excerpts, interviews, and obituary, 1985 (Box 50)
    - Gardner, Amanda, Project Demonstrating Excellence, Temporary Spaces: Reflections on Dislocation, Writing, and Community, 2005 April (2 folders) (Box 50)
    - Hecht, Joshua, Sexual Identity, Sex Acts, and the Plasticity of Truth, thesis conclusion, 2000 (Box 50)
    - Hyatt, Martin, A Scarecrow's Bible, proofs, 2005 (Box 50)
    - Kaier, Anne, If I Unbind, 2005 June (Box 50)
    - Mackler, Susan van Haften, The Women's Liberation Movement and It's Publications: An Exploratory Study of Two Movement Publications, The Feminist Newsletter and Ms., 1974 August (Box 50)
    - Mills, Laurel, I Sing Back, 1997 (Box 50)
    - Miscellaneous, 1990-1998 and undated (Box 50)
    - Rich, Adrienne, Dead Power, Living Power: Notebooks on Poetry and Politics, undated (2 folders) (Box 50)
    - Zipter, Yvonne, The Patience of Metal (Box 50)
- Correspondence Series, 1968-2005 and undated, 24 boxes
  The Correspondence Series contains correspondence Pratt sent and received after 1966, the year of her marriage. Correspondence dated 1966 and prior is located in the Family Series. The Series comprises three subseries: Personal Correspondence, Literary Correspondence, and General Correspondence.
  - Personal Correspondence, 1968-2005 and undated, 17 boxes
    The subseries contains letters, notes, and emails pertaining to Pratt's personal life. Major correspondents appear first, arranged alphabetically by last name. Other miscellaneous correspondence follows, arranged chronologically. Written communication dated 1966 and prior appears in the Family Series. Notable correspondents include Dorothy Allison, Judith Arcana, Elly Bulkin, Chrystos, Holly Hughes, Audre Lorde, Adrienne Rich, and Mab Segrest.
    - Addison, Lois Anne, 1986-1991 (Box 51)
    - Allison, Dorothy, 1992, 1995 (Box 51)
    - Arcana, Judith, 1990-2005 (6 folders) (Box 51)
    - Biren, Joan, 1981-1988 (folder 1 of 5) (Box 51)
    - Biren, Joan, 1981-1988 (folders 2-5 of 5) (Box 52)
    - Biren, Joan, 1992-1993 (Box 52)
    - Bulkin, Elly, 1980-2005 (folders 1-3 of 6) (Box 52)
    - Bulkin, Elly, 1980-2005 (folder 4-6 of 6) (Box 53)
    - Choi, Don Mee, 2003-2005 (Box 53)
    - Chrystos, 1993-2003 (Box 53)
    - Cousins, 1992-2005 (3 folders) (Box 53)
    - Deming, Barbara, 1981-1984 (Box 54)
    - Derricotte, Toi, 1999-2001 (Box 54)
    - Ebersole, Lucinda, 1992-1998 (Box 54)
    - Frye, Marilyn, 1992-1993 (3 folders) (Box 54)
    - Gladney, Rose and Marcia Winter, 1988-1998 (Box 54)
    - Grant, Jaime, 1996-2000 (Box 54)
    - Grimsley, Jim, 1996-2000 (Box 54)
    - Hacker, Marilyn 2004 (Box 54)
    - Harris, Bertha, 1999-2000 (Box 54)
    - Harrison, Anne (cousin), 2001-2005 (Box 54)
    - Hiestrand, Bev (Beverly), 2001-2005 (folder 1 of 2) (Box 54)
    - Hiestrand, Bev (Beverly), 2001-2005 (folder 2 of 2) (Box 55)
    - Hughes, Holly, 1996-2005 (4 folders) (Box 55)
    - Klepfisz, Irena, 1993, 1995 (Box 55)
    - Knowlton, Elizabeth, 1979-1994 (Box 55)
    - Larkin, Joan, 1993-2001 (Box 55)
    - Levitsky, Rachel, 2000-2002 (Box 55)
    - Lorde, Audre, 1987-1990 (Box 55)
    - Mama, 1981-2001 (Box 55)
    - Mama and aunts, 1988, 1992-2005 (Box 55)
    - Mayr, Shellah, 1979-1982 (Box 56)
    - Mays, Ramina, 1983, 2001-2002 (Box 56)
    - McCann, Richard, 1997-2001 (Box 56)
    - McCullough, Bobby (Robert), 2000-2005 (Box 56)
    - McDaniel, Judith, 1983-1985, 1993-1998 (Box 56)
    - McDaniel, Judith and Maureen Brady, 1980-1992 (Box 56)
    - Meigs, Mary, 1980s (Box 56)
    - Minnich, Elizabeth, 2002-2005 (Box 56)
    - Mohanty, Chandra and Margo Okazawa-Rey, 2002-2005 (Box 56)
    - Mosbacher, Dee (Diane) and Nanette Gartrell (folders 1-3 of 4) (Box 56)
    - Mosbacher, Dee (Diane) and Nanette Gartrell (folder 4 of 4) (Box 57)
    - Pratt family, 1988-1989 (Box 57)
    - Pratt, Minnie Williams, 1980-1982 (Box 57)
    - Randall, Margaret, 1985-1990, 1998-2002 (Box 57)
    - Realuyo, Bino 1996-2000 (Box 57)
    - Rich, Adrienne, 1981-1996 (2 folders) (Box 57)
    - Segrest, Mab, 1982-2000 (2 folders) (Box 57)
    - Simon (grandson), undated (Box 57)
    - South, Cris, 1978-1979, 1982-1986 (folder 1 of 5) (Box 57)
    - South, Cris, 1978-1979, 1982-1986 (folders 2-5 of 5) (Box 58)
    - Vance, Diane, 1990 (Box 58)
    - Vinson, Darlene, 1982-1984 (Box 58)
    - Walter, Starling, 1986-1988 (Box 58)
    - Woodbury, Vera family, 1992-1993 (Box 58)
    - 1967 (Box 59)
    - 1968 (2 folders) (Box 59)
    - 1969 (3 folders) (Box 59)
    - 1970 (Box 59)
    - 1971 (2 folders) (Box 59)
    - 1972 (Box 59)
    - 1973 (Box 59)
    - 1974 (Box 59)
    - 1975 (Box 60)
    - 1976 (Box 60)
    - 1977 (Box 60)
    - 1978 (2 folders) (Box 60)
    - 1979 (4 folders) (Box 60)
    - 1980 (2 folders) (Box 61)
    - 1981 (2 folders) (Box 61)
    - 1982 (Box 61)
    - 1983 (Box 61)
    - 1984 (2 folders) (Box 61)
    - 1985 (2 folders) (Box 62)
    - 1986 (3 folders) (Box 62)
    - 1986-1988 (2 folders) (Box 62)
    - 1987 (2 folders) (Box 62)
    - 1988 (2 folders) (Box 63)
    - 1989 (3 folders) (Box 63)
    - 1989-1992 (2 folders) (Box 63)
    - 1990 (2 folders) (Box 63)
    - 1991 (2 folders) (Box 63)
    - 1992 (Box 64)
    - 1993 (3 folders) (Box 64)
    - 1994 (2 folders) (Box 64)
    - 1995 (2 folders) (Box 64)
    - 1996 (3 folders) (Box 65)
    - 1997 (Box 65)
    - 1998 (3 folders) (Box 65)
    - 1999 (folders 1-2 of 3) (Box 65)
    - 1999 (folder 3 of 3) (Box 66)
    - 2000 (3 folders) (Box 66)
    - 2001 (2 folders) (Box 66)
    - 2002 (Box 66)
    - Fall 2002-Spring 2003 (Box 66)
    - 2003 (2 folders) (Box 67)
    - 2004 (2 folders) (Box 67)
    - 2005 (2 folders) (Box 67)
  - Literary Correspondence, 1970-2005, 4 boxes
    The chronologically arranged subseries comprises book orders, communication with publishers, public relations, reviews, and other correspondence associated with Pratt's published writings.
    - 1970-1980 (2 folders) (Box 68)
    - Poetry, 1978 (Box 68)
    - 1981-1985 (2 folders) (Box 68)
    - 1986-1990 (folder 1 of 2) (Box 68)
    - 1986-1990 (folder 1-2 of 2) (Box 69)
    - 1991-1995 (2 folders) (Box 69)
    - 1996-1998 (Box 69)
    - This is What Lesbian Looks Like, 1998-1999 (Box 69)
    - 1999 (folders 1-2 of 4) (Box 69)
    - 1999 (folders 3-4 of 4) (Box 70)
    - 2000 (2 folders) (Box 70)
    - 2001 (Box 70)
    - 2002-2003 (folder 1 of 2) (Box 70)
    - 2002-2003 (folder 2 of 2) (Box 71)
    - Temple, 2002-2004 (Box 71)
    - 2004-2005 (Box 71)
  - General Correspondence, 1984-2005, 4 boxes
    Arranged chronologically, the subseries includes correspondence with acquaintances or individuals lacking a personal relationship with Pratt. Correspondence consists primarily of requests for recommendations, contacts, or appearances.
    - 1983 (Box 71)
    - 1984 (Box 71)
    - 1985 (Box 71)
    - 1986-1988 (Box 71)
    - 1992 (Box 71)
    - 1993-1995 (folder 1 of 2) (Box 71)
    - 1993-1995 (folder 2 of 2) (Box 72)
    - 1996 (Box 72)
    - 1997 (3 folders) (Box 72)
    - 1998 (Box 72)
    - 1999 (2 folders) (Box 72)
    - 2000 (folder 1 of 3) (Box 72)
    - 2000 (folders 2-3 of 3) (Box 73)
    - 2001 (3 folders) (Box 73)
    - 2002 (2 folders) (Box 73)
    - 2003 (folder 1 of 4) (Box 73)
    - 2003 (folders 2-4 of 4) (Box 74)
    - 2004 (2 folders) (Box 74)
    - 2005 (2 folders) (Box 74)
- Family Series, 1870s-2005 and undated, 15 boxes
  The Family Series contains materials related to Pratt's childhood and relatives, including legal and business papers, genealogical information, land grants and deeds, correspondence, mementos, and photographs. The bulk of the material dates to the twentieth century, but a few documents and several photographs date to the nineteenth century. Correspondence written after 1966, the year of Pratt's marriage, is located in the Correspondence Series. The Family Series comprises five subseries: Brown-Carr Family, Pratt Family, Minnie Bruce Pratt, Ransom Weaver and Ben Weaver, and Leslie Feinberg. The Brown-Carr Family subseries contains materials related to Pratt's maternal relatives. The Pratt Family subseries chiefly pertains to Pratt's mother, Virginia Brown Pratt, but contains some material related to Pratt family relatives. The Minnie Bruce Pratt subseries contains materials related to Pratt's childhood, including correspondence and mementos. Items in the Ransom Weaver and Ben Weaver subseries are primarily photographs and programs and magazines from Ransom's rowing events. All Leslie Feinberg materials are closed.
  - Brown-Carr Family, 1870s-2005 and undated, 6 boxes
    The subseries comprises legal papers, mementos, ledgers, land grants and deeds, clippings, writings, and photographs pertaining to Pratt's maternal relatives, the Browns and Carrs. Materials are arranged alphabetically by individual relatives and then by subject.
    - Brown, Janie Carr papers, 1942-1958 (Box 75)
    - Brown, Ora Gilder papers, 1944, 1964-1978, 1993-2005 (Box 75)
    - Brown, Ora Gilder, writings by Minnie Bruce Pratt about Brown, 2005 (Box 75)
    - Brown, Ora Gilder photographs, ca. 1870s-1900, 1920s, 1938, 1976, 1981, 2001-2005(3 folders) (Box 75)
    - Carr, James Ozborn, The Carr Family of Duplin County, 1920 (Box 75)
    - Carr, Robert papers, 1920, 1930s, 1946, 1950s, 1970s (Box 75)
    - Carr, Robert photographs, ca. 1900s-1920s, 1944, 1962 (Box 75)